你好黑客
hello hackers
欢迎观看动态分配器误用模块的下一个视频
welcome to the next video in the Dynamic Allocator Misuse module
我们要讨论堆的相关危险
we gonna be talking about the dangers of the heap
这样你能知道可能会犯哪些错
so you understand why conceptually humans can make errors
我相信你遇到过这些错误
I'm sure that you've observed humans making errors in the past
不一定是你自己，也许是你认识的人犯的
not necessarily yourselves but maybe someone you know
或者你可能听别人讲过有人犯这些错误
or maybe you've heard about murmurs of humans sometimes making errors
不管怎样，人们会误用堆
anyways people misuse the heap
为什么这会是一个问题
why is this a problem
因为堆的实现
well this is a problem because heap implementations
各种动态分配库
dynamic allocation libraries
它们经历了这样一个有趣的循环
they go through this interesting cycle
任何库都有开销
where any library has overhead
函数调用有开销
a function call has overhead
call指令有开销
the call instruction has overhead right and
分配器所做的每件事都会有一定的开销
and everything that the allocator does will have some amount of overhead
只要分配器存在开销
and when an allocator exists
就有应用开发人员会抱怨
application developers they will complain about this overhead
这个抱怨是合理的
and that's a legitimate complaint
应用开发人员都希望程序跑的快
application developers need things to be fast
内存分配器开发人员也会根据分配器的状态
allocator developers will look at the state of the allocator
改进它
and they will improve it
他们可能创建一个缓存层或其他优化
they will create a caching layer some other optimization etc
这必然会导致安全问题
this invariably leads to security issues
一个缓存错误可能有
a caching error might have
可能会引入严重的安全问题
might introduce significant security problems
这些问题可能各种各样
and these can come in all sorts of shapes and sizes
通常是在对堆的特定误用中
usually it's in the context of a specific misuse of the heap
安全将受到威胁
security will be compromised
从历史上看，分配器开发人员通常会反对安全性
the allocator developers typically push back against security historically
这对他们来说是说的通的
and this makes sense to them
分配器需要快速运行
the allocator needs to be fast
并且分配器应该被正确使用
and the allocator should be properly used
如果分配器使用不当
if the allocator is improperly used
如果是应用程序中的bug导致触发不安全状态
if bugs in an application lead to the triggering of insecure states
这是应用的问题，好吧
and allocator... well this is a problem with application
应用程序有bug
the application had the bug
应用程序开发人员应该修复他们的bug
the application developer should fix their bugs right
分配器开发者
and so allocator developers
通常对高开销的安全解决方案相当抵触
typically are fairly resistant to high overhead security solutions
他们想要速度
right they want speed
但问题总是会累积起来
but invariably problems build up
这种对安全的看法是在导致安全问题中排第二的原因
this view of security is secondary causes issues
大量的漏洞开始出现
a lot of exploits start emerging
应用的安全性受到威胁
security of applications is compromised
即使最初的bug是应用程序的问题
even if the initial bug was applications fault
但事实上
you know the fact that
因为在堆实现中的优化
because of an optimization layer in the heap implementation
最初的bug可能能够被利用
the original bug could be exploited
成为问题后
becomes a problem and then
分配器开发人员创建了一个修复
the allocator developers create a fix
这个修复将增加安全检查
and this fix will add security checks
这个安全检查会有开销
and security checks have overhead
而这种开销会引起应用开发人员的抱怨
and this overhead will cause application developers to complain
整个过程又将重新开始
and the process starts new all together
现在的 ptmalloc 处在这个阶段
right now in ptmalloc we are here
基本上
basically
旧的实现存在安全问题
there were security problems in the old implementation
它们会导致安全检查
they lead to security checks
这和其他原因一起
this among other things among other
比如多核系统的出现等等
you know the emergence of heavily multi core systems etc
更改了分配器的性能特征
changed the performance characteristics of the allocator
开发人员在这里创建一个缓存层
and the developers create a caching layer here
这严重降低了堆实现的安全性
which severely reduced the security of the heap implementation
这个缓存层就是 Tcache
this is tcache
我将在以后的视频中讨论它
and I'll talk about it in a later video
在现在的ubuntu 2004和libc 2.31以及以后的版本
and right now with the ubuntu 2004 with libc 2.31 and onwards
我们正开始解决tcache带来的问题
we are starting to fix the problems that tcache introduced
上次我教这门课的时候
last time I taught this course
这段视频是在2020年录制的
so this video is recorded in 2020 of course
2019年，我们还在使用ubuntu1804
in 2019 we were still on ubuntu1804
作为当时最新的长期支持(lts)版本
as the latest kind of long term support
我使用的是当时ubuntu最新的长期支持
I use the latest long term support of a ubuntu
作为课程的基准
as a baseline for the course of course
ubuntu18.04还处在这个阶段
and 1804 still had us here
所以实际上
so it was actually just
更容易实现一些我们将要讨论的技巧
a little bit easier to pull off some of the hacks that will be talking about
但并非全部如此。这对我们(当前)的研究深度影响很小
but not all. it's a very small impact on how deep we go
如果我们再深入一点
if we went much deeper
那就会有大影响了
then it would be an impact all right
那么堆是如何被误用的呢
so how can the heap be misused right
我已经列出了分配器安全性的生命周期
I've kind of laid out this life cycle of allocator security
但这一切都要看人在应用程序中犯的错误
but it all rests on humans making errors in applications
因为应用程序是攻击者攻击的对象
because the applications are what an attacker attacks
而不是堆本身
not the heap itself
它们通过应用程序到达堆
they get to the heap through the application
堆的错误使用有三种主要类型
and we have kind of three main categories of heap misuse
第一种是忘记释放内存
the first one is just forgetting to free memory
我们快速地讲一遍
right we're gonna cover this super quick
然后继续
and then move on
但这会导致资源枯竭
but this leads to resource exhaustion
第二种是忘记我们已经释放了内存
the second one is forgetting that we have freed memory
这是个很有趣的问题
which is a very interesting problem
这可能导致使用已经被释放的内存
that can lead to using memory that is free
而这会导致其他问题，我们稍后会讨论
that leads to other problems later as we'll discuss
还可能导致重复释放内存
and freeing memory that is free
这会导致其他问题
which leads to other problems later
最后一种是破坏元数据
and there is a danger of accidentally corrupting metadata
分配器使用这些元数据跟踪堆状态
that the allocator itself uses to keep track of heap state
可以类比栈上的缓冲区溢出
so you can imagine a buffer overflow on the stack
可以更改控制数据
you start collaborating control data
如返回地址
such as the return address
这和堆非常相似
it's very similar for the heap
如果堆上有缓冲区溢出
if you have a buffer overflow on the heap
您可以开始修改堆元数据
you can start collaborating heap metadata
堆会变得异常
and the heap goes insane
好吧
all right
我们展开讲一下这3点
let's touch on each one piece by piece
首先是内存泄漏
first memory leaks
只要你使用过堆，你就很可能都遇到过这个问题
you've all probably seen this if you have use the heap in any way
如果你malloc了片内存
if you malloc something
你忘了在你失去所有对它的引用之前释放它
and you forget to free it before you lose all references to it
在你失去指针之前
before you lose the the pointers
像这里的问题
in question like here
指针是局部变量，函数执行完它就消失了
the pointer is local variable and it's gone
它没有被释放
it was not freed
那这个blah指向内存会发生什么
what happened to the memory pointed by blah
当然
right of course
这块内存就在那里
the memory stays around
它停留在数据段中等待
it stays there in the data segment waiting
等待着被释放
and waiting to be freed
直到进程结束，它才会被释放
and it is never freed until the process dies
为什么这是一个问题
why is this an issue
这是个问题
well it could be an issue
因为这些数据可能是敏感的
because it could become an issue if that data is sensitive
你可能在那里有敏感的密码
right so you might have some sensitive password in there
或者是你再也无法从内存中抹去的东西
or something that you can no longer scrub from memory
其他漏洞可能会暴露它，这是一个问题
and other bugs could expose it that's one problem
另一个问题是你可能会耗尽你的资源
another problem is that you can exhaust your resources
通常这不是安全问题
usually this isn't a security issue
但这也可能是的
but it can be
让我给你看一个有趣的东西
let me show you an interesting thing
我写了一个简短的程序
I wrote up a quick program
它只会分配大量的内存
that just allocates huge chunks of memory
当malloc执行成功
while it's successful
当返回一个合法指针a
so when a returns a pointer
就能一直malloc
we keep doing this
最终
eventually
我们会耗尽可以分配的内存
we're gonna run out of memory that we can allocate
Malloc，如果你看手册页，会失败
malloc if you look at the man page can actually fail
如果出现错误，这些函数返回null
on error, these functions return null
malloc可以返回null
so malloc can return null
让我们来编译它
let's compile it
在过去
you know back in the day
这会直接破坏（覆盖）我的C代码
this would simply destroy my C code
我很高兴他们加了检查
I'm glad that they added a check for that
好吧
all right
如果运行这个
if you run this
32767之后
after 32,767
非常接近2的16次方
which is very suspiciously close to 2 to the sixteenth
呃分配
uh allocations
下一次分配失败了
our next allocation fails
我们得到一个NULL
and we just get a null
就返回了
that's return
这可能不是坏事
this might not be bad
这取决于应用程序
depending on what's going on with the program
如果你检查一下
if you check
显然这里
obviously if here
如果我们检查malloc的返回值
if we check the return value of malloc
就像隐式地循环执行，循环能终止
like being implicitly doing this wild loop
这很好，但如果程序不检查它
that's fine but if a program doesn't check it
那就会发生各种奇怪的事情
then all sorts of weird stuff can happen
通常是访问0地址内存之类的
usually it'll be access to memory at 0 or something
对的，如果我往a中拷贝一个字符串
right if I then did a whatever strcpy something into a
就会出现空指针异常
it would just seg fault on a null pointer do reference
但是a，malloc返回值，也有其他用途
but there could be other uses of a or of a the return of malloc
这可能有很大安全影响
that could be security critical or
例如，如果这发生在内核中
if this happens in the kernel for example
内核可能会挂
the whole kernel could die
这不是一个（我们关注的）安全问题
so it's not a big security issue
在这张幻灯片了解一下就好
you're not going to actually bother with it other than this slide
但这是值得考虑的问题
but it is something to think about
仅仅只是忘记释放内存
even just forgetting to free an allocation
就能对程序产生影响
can have some impact to the program
好吧
all right
让我们来看看真正的东西
let's go on to real stuff
释放后重用
right use after free
还记得
remember
类似于栈上的内存分配
similar analogous to the allocation on the stack
实际上并没有清除那里的数据
not actually wiping out the data there
概念上与之相似
you know conceptually similar to that
当释放指针指向的内存时
when you call free on a pointer
如果你申请了内存
if you malloc something like this
然后你释放它
and then you free it
那个指针还在那里
that pointer is still there
它依然指向那片旧内存
this still point at the old piece of memory
为什么这不好?
why is this bad
不好的原因是
this is bad because
如果你忘了已经读过了，然后
if you forget that you've read it and this happens
显然在这个小例子中
obviously in the small example
是故意的
it you know this is a little contrived
但在大型应用程序中，这种情况经常发生
but in a large application this happens depressingly frequently
如果你忘了你释放了什么
if you forget that you freed something
然后又使用了它
and you then use it
它仍然是有效的内存
this is still valid memory
问题是这一刻的它是空闲的
the problem is this memory the moment is free
分配器可以用它干别的
the allocator could reuse it for something else
在这个例子中
in this example
当我们释放了user_input
when we free our user input
然后分配一个变量
and we allocate a variable
它用于确认用户是否被认证
that tells us if we are authenticated or not
当我们在这里 输入时
when we then scanf here
其实我们写入了authenticated变量
we are overriding our authenticated variable
我们写在了这里
we're writing exactly into there
好让我们
alright let's
我来举个例子
let me show you this in an example
这是释放重用的例子
here's our use after free on the heap um
和幻灯片中的一样
the exactly the what what you saw in the previous slide
好的，我们编译它
alright we compile that
所以
so again
实际上我们
actually let's
我们先不演示释放重用
let's first compile it without the use after free
假设我们没有释放堆
let's say we did not free the heap
这里的用户输入变量
the user input variable here
我们编译它，运行这个程序
we compile it we run this heap UAF
姓名Yan，输出你好Yan，密码
name Yan says hello Yan password
我不知道密码是多少
I don't know what the password is
它什么也不做
it doesn't do anything
让我们得到密码
let's get the the password
当然
of course
你知道怎么通过逆向工程获取密码
you know how to reverse engineer for a password
Yan 密码
Yan password
呃boom
uh boom
好的
all right
这是有道理的
so this makes sense right
也很明显
also obviously
如果你注意看的话（判断了uid是否等于0）
if you're paying attention
如果我以root用户运行
if I run this as root
我输入一个随机密码
and I put in a random password
boom，它成功了
boom it works
好吧，让我们恢复这个free
okay anyways let's restore this free
编译它
compile it
用用户Yan运行
run it as a just a user name Yan
密码，随机的或者不是正确的
password something random or not the correct password
它仍然成功了
and it still works
为什么，不好意思，为什么它还能用
why excuse me why does it still work
它有效是因为
it works because
如果我们打印出user_input的地址
if we print out the address of user input
再打印出authenticated的地址
and we print out the address of authenticated
我们编译
and we compile
执行
and we run
所以user_input在是2b22a0
so user input is at this 2b22a 0
authenticated 位于同一位置
authenticated is at the same location
因为我们在这里释放了user_input
because we freed the user input here
堆认为它没用了
the heap thinks it's no longer used
这个指针没有改变
this pointer hasn't changed
但是现在当我们这样做的时候
but now when we do this
我们现在写了authenticated指向的内存
we are now overriding the memory that authenticated points to
authenticated指向的内存
that authenticated pointer
而不是我们所想的user_input缓冲区
rather than what we're thinking of is the user input buffer
这个缓冲已经不存在了
that buffer no longer exists
很酷的
cool
好的，这是释放重用
all right so this is used after free here
哦
oops
这是那个讲C的书
that is the C book
技术问题先别急
hold on technical issues one second
好吧
all right
让我们
let's
这里我们看到了覆盖其它变量的问题
so so there we saw an overwrite of a different variable
释放重用可能会产生许多严重后果
use after free can have many many brutal consequences
释放重用的存在的原则是
the bottom line in use after free is
不同时期不同变量的内存有重叠
you have something that is basically overlapping memory with two meanings
这是个坏消息
and that's bad news
我待会再讨论这个问题
I'll revisit that in a sec all right
另一个危险
another danger
内存信息泄露
memory disclosure
如果不往user_input里写
what if instead of writing to user input
而是从内存里读user_input呢
we had read from it right
一个简单的例子
the simple case
一个能说的通的例子
the case that makes sense
你可以想象一下
you could imagine that
程序不再存储一个authenticated变量
instead of storing an authenticated variable
而是在那里存储了一个密码
the program stored a password there right
然后我们可以用printf读取密码
and then we could read out that password with a printf
但一个复杂的情况是
but a complicated case is that
一些堆实现包括
some heap implementations including
我们主要关注的Ptmalloc
ptmalloc which is predominantly
它也是我们在作业中会用到的
which is what we'll be using in the homework and so forth
它会重新使用
reuse
这些释放过的内存块
the memory space of those freedom chunks
来存储关于块本身的元数据
to store metadata about the chunks themselves
稍后我们将对此进行深入讨论
we will talk about this in depth later
但现在先考虑这个程序
but for now considered this program
它先释放name缓冲区
where we free the name buffer
然后打印name缓冲区中的一些东西
and then we print something in the name buffer
好吧，让我们看看
all right let's take a look
好吧，抱歉
all right sorry
我们打印出了name缓冲区，对吧
we print out the name buffer right
当然，这在小程序中明显是人为的
this of course in a small program is kind of contrived
但这在现实生活中确实经常发生
but it does happen in real life a lot
好吧，快速看一下
all right take a quick look
嗯
um
下面是我们的堆泄露
here is our heap disclosure
会说你好，我们的名字
it'll say hello our name
它会问我们密码
it'll ask us for our password
老实说，这样做是为了设置堆
honestly they're doing this to warm up the to set up the heap
然后它会问我们的名字
then it'll ask us for our name
然后它会在释放name后打印再见name
and then it will print goodbye our name after freeing our name
好的，运行它
okay so run it
密码
password
名字
name
所以它说你好
so it says hello
Yan
然后它就释放了
then it frees
释放了name，然后说再见name
does this free name and then says goodbye
这应该是Yan，但现在不是Yan了
and what should be Yan but it's not Yan anymore
而是一些乱码
it's some crazy stuff
让我们把它通过管道传给
let's pipe it through
复制它
copy it
通过管道传给hexdump
i'll just pipe it through hexdump
输入密码
put the password
名字，好了
the name all right
它问了我密码
so it had told me password
然后我输入密码，它问我名字
and then I put in the password and it asked me for the name
说你好，Yan，这里说再见
says hello Yan and here says goodbye
然后是一些东西
and then some stuff
好的，到感叹号这部分是什么东西
right and what is this stuff up to the exclamation point
感叹号在ASCII中是0x21
exclamation point in ASCII is hex 21
在它之前是07752a0
so before that it had 07 75 02 a0
好吧
all right
等一下，让我重执行一遍
hold on let me rerun that
我可能不走运遇到了空字节
I think we got unlucky with a null byte
好了
there we go
好了，我们不像之前碰到了一个空字节
all right we have gotten unlike it with a null byte
当然，printf会在空字节处停止
of course printf stops on a null byte
它说再见，然后这里
so it says goodbye and then here
55 71 7c 8C f2 a0
这看起来像一个堆地址
this looks like a heap address right let's run
让我们再运行这个程序，将结果传给hexdump
this heap disclosure through a hex dump
在另一边
in a different thing
我们打印出它的进程映射
let's cut out its mappings
堆位于557b20
the heap is at 55 7b20
哦，对不起，557b 230b 8000
oh sorry 55 7b 23 0B 80 00
密码，名字
password name
557 b 230 b
557b 230b
当然，它是堆中的某个地址
and then of course it's partially some address in the heap
82 a0
好的，通过
all right so with a
通过使用释放后的东西
by using something after its freed
我们可以泄露内存
we can disclose memory
泄露堆的元数据
disclose metadata that the heap uses
或其他数据
or other
如果它现在已经被重新分配并且正在使用
if it has now been allocated again and is being used
就会泄露其它应用程序使用的数据
disclosed information other data used by the program
和
and
抱歉，我愣了一下
sorry I'm having a brain dump one second
好吧
okay
然后
and
从那里获得程序的信息
you know from there gain knowledge by the program
通过内存错误，ROP等等
you know from memory errors and ROP and so forth
你应该知道一个指针有多有用
how useful knowing a pointer can be
好吧
all right
堆的终级危险：元数据破坏
the ultimate danger of the heap metadata corruption
我们刚刚读出了元数据
we just read out that metadata right
如果我们写入元数据呢
what if we wrote over that metadata right
这会导致分配器发疯
this causes the allocator to go insane
分配器信任它的元数据
the allocator trusts its metadata
它非常不愿意不相信这些元数据
and it is very reluctant not to trust this metadata
因为这需要开发高消耗的处理功能
because that causes costly workarounds to be developed right
这是关于安全性与性能的一个重要争论
this is one of the big security versus performance arguments
元数据究竟有多可信
is how trustworthy is this metadata
事实证明它根本不值得信任
turns out it's not trustworthy at all
我们知道这一点已经20年了
and we've known this for two decades now
回到2000年
back in the year 2000
太阳设计师
Solar Designer
你已经在ROP模块中认识过太阳设计师
you have seen Solar Designer in the module on return orient programming
太阳设计师创造、建议或至少发表
Solar Designer created or proposed or at least published
过原始的ret2libc技术
on the original return to libc technique
太阳设计师还
turns out Solar Designer also
开发了一个早期的堆元数据破坏漏洞利用方法
developed one of the early heap metadata corruption exploits
创建于2000年
created in 2000
到2001年，这在黑客文献中被确定下来
by 2001 this was formalized in hacker literature
具体来说，你可以看到这两篇phrack的文章
specifically you can see these two phrack articles
很久很久以前的事了
you know very very long time ago
人们破坏元数据，做一些疯狂的事情
people were corrupting metadata and doing crazy stuff
或者强迫分配器做一些疯狂的事情
or forcing the allocator to do crazy stuff
这是现在黑客界的一个完整的流派
this is now a whole genre in the hacking scene
为什么它是一种流派
why is it a genre in part
因为人们对它有点疯狂
because people went a little crazy with it
一个名叫Phantasmal Phantasmagoria的黑客
hacker by the name of Phantasmal Phantasmagoria
开发了一套关于堆元数据损坏的知识
developed the lore around heap metadata corruption
并且这个2005年的邮件列表
and this mailing list in 2005
在堆元数据损坏攻击被发明的五年后
five years after the invention of Heap metadata corruption attacks
或者至少是关于它们的第一次讨论
or at least the first discussion of them
Phantasmal Phantasmagoria
描述了一些这样的技术
described a bunch of these techniques
给他们起了这些疯狂的名字
and named that these insane names
人们
that people are
目前尚不清楚为什么选择这些名字
it's not clear why these names were chosen
但是人们延用了这个格式
but people really jumped on them
有house of prime，house of mind
there's you know the house of prime the house of mind
house of force等
the house of force etc
这些中的很多到现在依旧有用
are many of these stayed around until very recently
house of force在
the house of force was valid as of
上次我用ubuntu 1804教这门课时依旧有效
the last time I taughted this class in ubuntu 1804
你仍然可以尝试用house of force
you can still do house of force
但不幸的是，现在它已经有点落后了
but now it is unfortunately behind us
house of spirit还是可以用的
the house of spirit is still doable
这很不可思议，对吧?
which is incredible right
我们会在以后的几个视频中学习它
and we'll learn about it a couple of videos from now
然后事情很快就失控了
and then things got out of hand quick
所以人们开始创造出更多的house系列
so people have started adding more and more houses
探索出新的搞堆技术
as they discover additional techniques to mess with the heap
最近的趋势是house of
a recent trend has gotten to making house of
加上你的handle
and then your handle
比如house of Orange, house of botcake等等
so there's house of Orange House of botcake etc
这些对堆漏洞的研究不会停止
these are a perpetual study of heap vulnerability
你可以在一个repository里看到这些研究
and you can actually see these houses explored
由黑客团队Shellphish提供
in a repository from Hacking Team Shellphish
我在这个团队打了10年Defcon
the Hacking Team with whom I competed at Defcon for 10 years
他们维护了一个列表，里面有很多不同的libc攻击
they maintain a list of a whole lot of different libc attacks
比如house of spirit
for example house of spirit
你可以浏览
and you can click through
看到它在不同版本的libc中是如何工作的
and you can see how it works for different versions of libc
他们有一个C程序
they have a C programs that actually
或者看一下house of botcake吧
or house of botcake
这个程序演示了攻击
that demonstrate the attack against themselves
非常漂亮的东西
pretty pretty slick stuff
顺便说一下
by the way
如果你在经营一个黑客俱乐部
if you're running a hacking club
我强烈建议你这样做
I highly recommend doing something like this
当我们创建house of 的时候 house of 哈哈
when we created house of house of
在shellphish创建的"如何heap"
when we created how to heap with shellphish
就是我们学习堆的方法
this is how we Learned the heap
通过创建这个存储库
by creating this repository
太好了
it was incredible
好吧
all right
不管怎样
anyways
这里有很多不同的技术
a lot of the the various techniques here
有很多，不是全部
many of them not all and
很多不同安全相关的滥用策略
many of the different strategies toward abusing for security reasons
程序中的堆错误
a heap bug in a program
都与欺骗分配器返回重叠分配有关
has to do with trying to trick the allocator into returning overlapping allocations
或者说返回重叠的内存
or into returning overlapping memory
基本上如果在你的程序中有
basically if you have in your program
指向同一内存的两个指针
two pointers that point to the same memory
但其中一个指针被视为安全关键因素
but one of those pointers is treated as a security critical thing
就像我们在示例中看到的身份校验变量一样
like an authentication variable as we saw in an example
或者一个函数指针或者其他一些程序元数据等等
or a function pointer or some other program metadata etc
另一个不被视为安全关键
and the other one is not treated as security critical
例如，允许直接向它写入用户输入
for example allowing user input to be written directly to it
这里说的是程序期望的正常用户输入
by the normal operation of the program
然后游戏结束
then its game over
你的程序被入侵了
your program has been compromised
这能被直接攻破
this can be a direct compromise
以安全关键的视角看那块内存
if you are security critical view of that memory
你认为它是专门用来存储状态结构体的
you think is dedicated to holding some state
里面有函数指针
structure that has function pointers in it
随着这些函数指针
and you follow those function pointer
你直接调用这些函数指针
you call directly to those function pointers
然后通过另一个视角进入相同的内存
and then through a different view into the same memory
因为重叠的分配
because of an overlapping allocation
因为堆误用，您可以覆盖这些指针
because of a heap misuse you can override those pointers
显然，您可以劫持控制流
obviously you can redirect control flow
通常还有元数据
oftentimes there is metadata
比如其他结构的长度
such as the length of some other structure for example
你可以重写它
that you can overwrite
这就导致
and then this causes
一些更传统的漏洞
there are sometimes more traditional vulnerabilities
例如栈上的溢出
such as overflows on the stack for example
通常就是敏感数据
oftentimes there's just straight up sensitive data
存储在堆上的敏感数据
that is on the living in the heap
你能找到一个和它有重叠的变量
that you can get an overlap
然后读出敏感数据
and read it out
在这个模块的挑战问题中你一般会
in general what you will see  and do with the challenge problems for this module
尝试些疯狂的方法
is trying to do really crazy stuff
来得到重叠分配
to get overlapping allocations
然后滥用它来获得flag
and then abuse that to get the flag
现在我们将深入探讨
and now we will dive deeper into
你将要尝试的疯狂方法
the crazy stuff you will be doing